[Silo leader] Any spoken request
to leave the Silo is granted.
but it is irrevocable.
You have been asked to clean
and have been provided
with materials to do so.
but you cannot be forced into cleaning.
Once outside the air lock.
you are outside the law.
Have you any last words?
Sorry for all the fuss.
- [door lock clicks]
- [air hissing]
[Silo leader]
We do not know why we are here.
We do not know who built the Silo.
We do not know why everything
outside the Silo is as it is.
We do not know when
it will be safe to go outside.
We only know that day...
- [Holston breathes heavily]
- [Silo leader] ...is not this day.
[door lock clicks]
[whooshing]
[Holston breathes heavily]
[Silo residents chattering]
[Silo resident 1] Why'd he say it?
I can't believe they're sending
the sheriff out to clean.
You know. once he said it.
they didn't have any choice.
But why would the sheriff wanna go out?
[Silo resident 2] It's happening.
[Silo resident 3] Oh. shit. He's coming.
[Silo resident 2] Oh. no.
[Silo resident 4] Come on.
Damn it. Allison.
You were right.
[birds chirping]
[Holston breathes heavily. chuckling]
They have to see.
[breathes heavily. chuckling]
[sighs]
[cheering]
- How much?
- Ten.
You bet ten credits he wouldn't clean?
They always clean.
Can he last three minutes before
the poison gets him? That's the bet.
[Holston breathing heavily]
[groans]
[crowd murmuring]
[Silo resident 5] Come on. Sheriff!
[Holston wheezing]
[Holston gasping]
[Silo resident 6] What's he doing?
- [crowd gasping]
- Has anyone taken their helmet off before?
[gasping]
- [Silo resident 7] Get up!
- [crowd chattering]
Where's he going?
To be with his wife.
[gasping. wheezing]
[Silo resident 8]
The sheriff's dead. What happens now?
[Juliette] Fucking liar.
He's a fucking liar!
[crowd clamoring]
[Silo resident 9] Hey! Hey! Cut it out!
Stop now! Come on.
Listen up! Everybody. calm down!
Listen up!
That is fucked up. no question.
But it is no excuse for us
to lose our shit.
If anybody's gonna fight over a sheriff
being sent out to clean.
let them fight Up Top or in the Mids.
Here. in the Down Deep.
it's none of our business.
Our business is keeping the lights on.
[crowd] Yes!
[Silo resident 9]
Keeping the generator running.
[crowd] Yes!
[Silo resident 9] Keeping the Silo alive!
[crowd] Yeah!
[Silo resident 9] Here in the Down Deep.
we'll just get shit done. Okay?
[crowd] Yeah!
Okay?
[crowd cheering]
[screams]
- Okay?
- [screams]
- [crowd] Yeah!
- [screaming. grunting]
[knocks]
- You got a message from Karins.
- [groans]
We've been getting more alerts
about people lining up at Recycling.
trying to get their hands on pipes.
hammers...
Yeah. People are boneheads.
Well. people are scared.
Yeah. I'm gonna check in with everybody.
uh. on the radio.
Do you want anything from the cafeteria?
You should go home. Sandy.
Oh. he really loved her.
If you're wondering why.
[breathes shakily] Yeah.
[breathes shakily]
- [door opens]
- [Marnes] I'm a size medium. by the way.
[Silo leader chuckles] Maybe 20 years ago.
[inhales deeply]
The Jensen baby's due next week.
I used to be able to knock out 25
of these a year. one for every tenth kid.
Now I'm lucky if I do five.
- Drink?
- Yeah.
Day like today.
I think we get the good stuff.
[grunts]
[Silo leader]
Comes from before the rebellion.
Maybe before everything.
Thank you.
To Holston Becker.
[inhales shakily]
You decide who you're gonna pick
for sheriff?
I'm not looking at him?
I'll help break in the next one.
but I'm going to retire.
[inhales] When Jamal was retiring.
he chose Holston to be sheriff.
That was easy.
If Holston had been retiring.
I could've just followed his wishes.
but now...
Judicial will try and slip
one of their people into the post.
Holston didn't say anything to you?
[sighs]
I've been looking through
the mayor's ledgers. I'm up to 97.
Births. Deaths. How much water was used
that year. How many computer cables.
Was anyone sent out?
So far. not a single instance
of a mayor sending a sheriff out to clean.
He went out. but you didn't send him.
I didn't bring this up 'cause I feel sorry
for myself.
I brought it up 'cause I don't know what
happened before these ledgers existed.
Before the rebellion?
Before whatever caused the rebellion.
You worry it was a cleaning?
- I worry about instability.
- Yeah.
That's why we need
a new sheriff as soon as possible.
[sighs]
[vendor] This is the last one we've got.
[Silo resident 10] Thank you.
I need this.
- No. you're not getting it. No! You...
- No. I need this.
- No. you can't have my fucking hammer!
- [officer] Hey!
- Stop this shit!
- I need to protect my family!
- [Silo resident 10] Put the hammer down.
- [officer] Hey! Cut that shit out!
[both groaning. grunting]
[Silo resident 10] Shit. Judicial.
Shit.
Deputy Brooks.
Mr. Sims. I got this under control.
[chuckles]
Get their names.
[radio static]
[dispatcher 1]
Any idea when we'll get a new sheriff?
[beeps]
'Cause there's still a long line
at our local Recycling.
and the deputy asked me to make sure
we have enough ammunition.
[radio static]
[dispatcher 2] Level 14 is clear.
[door slams]
- What are you doing?
- What does it look like?
It looks like you showed up in a bad mood.
Now. you're taking it out on that toaster.
No. I'm fixing it.
Oh. You've been coming in here
since you were 13...
Oh. here we go.
...to fix shit.
so you don't have to deal with shit.
Can you just let me work alone. please?
This have anything to do with what
you said after the sheriff cleaned?
Because Shirley came by last night.
She said you stormed out. yelling.
"He lied!"
Don't think I was yelling.
You know what? Coming in here.
sitting in that chair. using my tools.
that's a privilege.
And the only way you get to stay here
is by telling me what in hell's going on.
Okay. then I won't stay.
You didn't come here to mend a toaster.
You came here to talk.
I know that's hard for you.
Okay. Take your time.
[Juliette sighs]
It's about George.
It's been three months since he died.
- You're saying he lied?
- No. Holston lied.
- You still think George was murdered?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. 'cause he didn't kill himself. so...
- How can you be so sure?
'Cause the last time I saw him.
he really wanted to show me something.
We were celebrating Cooper
becoming my shadow.
George was always paranoid
'cause we weren't sanctioned.
so he never came to these things.
- [Silo resident 11] Computer guy!
- [chuckles]
They're making me get drunk.
Well. it looks like you're
putting up a fight.
- [laughs]
- Coop.
why don't we get you some water
and a chair?
Cake?
Hey. everyone knows about us.
They don't give a shit.
They're not gonna send us to the mines.
[George]
You'd be fine down there. tough girl.
[chuckles]
Hey. uh... Something happened.
Something big.
I can't tell you here.
but can I speak to you after?
Yeah. sure. I work until late.
Oh. uh.
then I'll-I'll tell you at your place.
Okay.
[Silo resident 9] Everybody!
Where's Coop?
- Get Coop up here.
- Oh.
This is all about him. Come here.
Coop. I know you're freaking the fuck out.
- You are ready to shadow Jules.
- Gotta go.
[Silo resident 9]
Let's all give it up for Cooper! Come on.
[crowd cheering]
[Juliette] When I got off work
at midnight. I was exhausted.
I was looking forward to seeing George.
[Juliette] George?
- Hey.
Well. you don't look too hungover.
I'm not. Just sad.
Why?
- You didn't hear?
- I just got up. Hear what?
Computer George went off
the stairs last night.
They're saying suicide.
Did you know him well?
[breathes heavily]
[gasps]
Look. Jules.
I don't know what you want me to say.
[stammers] I really liked the guy.
And suicide is a crime against the Silo.
- I know.
- If you have proof that he didn't jump.
you'd be saving me
a mountain of paperwork. But...
But murder?
And by who? And why?
I don't know!
I just know he didn't kill himself. Hank.
Okay. see. for it to be murder.
you need more than that.
- You need motive and opportunity.
- Don't fucking patronize me. Hank.
Hey. I'm not patronizing you. it's just...
What? Hmm?
I know you two were...
I figured. down here. who cares?
The thing is.
if you were in a sanctioned relationship.
this would be easier.
A partner has certain rights.
Yeah. Well... [sniffles]
Fuck it.
I'll run your concerns Up Top.
I'll say it came from a coworker
who knew him well.
See what the sheriff has to say.
He's a good man.
Nobody likes a suicide.
[grunts] Come on! [strains]
[grunts]
[Hank] That's her.
- [Holston] What's her name?
- What?
[Marnes] What's her name?
Juliette.
Juliette Nichols.
The body was found here.
on this ventilation unit.
I'm thinking George must've fallen
maybe 100 feet. give or take.
No witnesses.
So. nothing much more I can give you.
You seem awfully tense.
Oh. I... I'm always tense. sir.
I get it. Suicide is a serious crime.
- No. it wasn't suicide.
- So you've said.
Yeah. He wasn't depressed.
He wasn't giving anything away.
There was no sudden elation
that he finally made a decision
that he would...
We're all taught those signs so early.
people get good at hiding them.
How'd you know him?
Oh. uh. George...
Everybody knows everybody down here.
And George was the funny computer guy.
[Holston]
Why do you think he was murdered?
He have any enemies?
I just know he...
[stammers] I told her. for murder.
you need motive and opportunity and...
Yeah. but I told you we have opportunity.
He died at 3:00 a.m?
No one's on the stairs then. Right?
[Holston] Unless you're a porter.
Or going to jump.
Go to Dispatch. would you?
See if there were any porters
on the stairs when it happened.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
That's a nice watch. Is that a relic?
- Um. it's... it's legal.
- Just said it was nice.
Look. I'm sorry about your coworker.
I'm gonna go look at his body again.
Check for any signs of a struggle.
Okay.
Hate to ask. but maybe there's something
you'd see that I don't.
But only if you're up to it.
Uh. no. yeah. Of... Of course.
Yeah. sure. Cool.
[Holston]
We're looking for anything unusual.
Abrasions that wouldn't be consistent
with a fall. Evidence of a fight.
- You ready?
- Yep.
[grunts]
Some people...
cut their wrists in previous attempts.
Then they decide to be sure...
so they jump.
Even after all these years.
I haven't gotten used to the sight.
- You ever seen...
- Dead person? Yeah.
My brother when I was 12.
My mother when I was 13. But. you know...
[chuckles. sniffles] ...you knew that. so...
[clicks tongue]
Someone says murder. you look into them.
Find out what reason
they might have for saying that...
The reason is 'cause he was murdered.
That's why.
But you might not wanna believe
it's suicide. given your history.
That's something I can understand.
[door opens]
- [Marnes] Anything new?
- [door closes]
[Holston] Not really. [sighs]
What they say at Dispatch?
It was a quiet night for the porters.
Nobody up or down.
- Judicial's on their way.
- Okay.
[Hank] Possible suicide and all.
they want a briefing.
You guys. uh. ask around.
See if there was anyone else
on the stairs.
All right.
You want something to eat?
No.
How long
were you and George in a relationship?
I won't tell anybody.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Why didn't you get sanctioned?
Why not?
Look.
if we're gonna figure out what happened.
you're gonna have to tell me the truth.
When you went to my deputy
and said murder.
you wanted help. right?
He didn't kill himself.
- Okay.
- [sighs]
I gotta go meet with Judicial.
Juliette. the not knowing.
it's gonna haunt you forever.
[whispers] He left something for me.
What?
You being sheriff and me.
not being sheriff.
I need you to promise me
you're not gonna rat me out to Judicial.
Is it a relic?
'Cause if it is.
I'm gonna have to confiscate it.
No. he didn't leave me anything.
Nothing to show you.
But who's to say where I found it?
The Silo's a big place.
[sighs]
[keys rattle]
What is this?
I don't know.
Maybe it was his way of saying goodbye.
Giving you something.
He left this with it.
Where's the rest of it?
That's all there was. I don't know.
"Remember where you last saw this?"
What I'm about to show you
is more illegal than any relic.
I'm sure Up Top knows about it.
but they don't seem to care.
I'm from Up Top
and I have no idea where we're going.
[sighs] Our agreement still apply?
Yeah.
[whispers] All right.
[grunts]
[Juliette sighs]
I hope you're not afraid of the dark.
Or tight spaces.
Or heights.
- [Holston] Who did all this?
- [Juliette] I don't know.
We think it's from before the rebellion.
Hey. Careful.
[Juliette inhales sharply]
- What's down there?
- You'll see.
[grunting]
[exhales sharply]
[grunts]
[exhales deeply]
Thanks.
There were probably
a hundred work lights here at one time.
[sighs] Only these ones are left.
[Holston] What is that?
[Juliette] Best guess is what's left
of the machine that dug the Silo.
Theory goes. digger comes down this far.
there's no easy way to get it out.
so the founders just walled it off
with a 30-foot cap of concrete.
Digger must have looked like this for.
pfft. a hundred years.
Anything of value
has been stripped a long time ago.
First time I saw this place.
it made me realize
how little we know about the Silo.
Ready?
Oh. um. it's better not to look down.
You okay?
[breathes shakily]
What is this place?
[Juliette] George.
He put it all together.
Last time I saw this thing was...
Was down here.
[exhales heavily]
Was in this box.
[Juliette grunts]
These are why he wanted
to keep us a... a secret.
You know. if he ever got caught with them.
he didn't want me sucked in.
Are these all relics?
Yeah.
I don't know...
Never seen this one before.
Maybe it's what he wanted you to see?
No idea what it is.
So. George sold and traded relics?
Yeah.
He was obsessed with the before time.
You know. he'd come down here on his own
and he'd be looking for something.
- Looking for what?
- I don't know. He never told me.
He just said
that he'd know it if he saw it.
That's odd.
This plastic wire
used to be wrapped around the spool.
Wait. Hold on.
What is this?
[breathing shakily]
What is that?
You see any of this before?
No.
He never mentioned this?
Said what might be on it?
No.
"Instructions on
how to recover deleted files."
[Juliette]
There's handwriting on the back.
That's not George's handwriting.
It's my wife's.
Do you think your wife knew George?
Allison did some IT work for him
not long before she went out.
Wh... Why didn't you tell me that?
Huh?
If George and your w...
[Holston sighs]
Did... Did you talk to him?
Once.
Oh. shit. The watch. [breathes shakily]
You'd seen it before. hadn't you?
That's why you checked his wrists.
That's... That's why...
That's why you knew we were together.
Is... Is that why you're here?
To see if I had anything to do
with why your wife went out to clean?
I came down here
to determine his cause of death.
Bullshit! You're wondering
if George had anything to do
with why your wife went out to clean.
And I'm gonna have to tell Judicial
his death was an accident.
Wh... Why? Why would you do that?
He was murdered!
- By who?
- I don't know by who!
There's a reason why George hid this.
Maybe it'll tell us why... why...
What happened to him.
I don't know
why he hid a fucking hard drive.
This is a red-level relic.
making it a threat to order in the Silo.
I don't care about the order in the Silo.
I want you to do your job!
Maintaining order in the Silo is my job.
What about finding out the truth?
I've gotta get this into the incinerator
before anyone else finds it.
- No.
- That's enough!
Maybe if you'd listened to your wife.
she'd still be alive right now!
[Holston breathing shakily]
To get to my office.
I have to walk through the cafeteria.
So. now I go to work before dawn.
and I come home after dark
just so I don't
have to see her body on that hill.
Allison asked questions too.
She was never afraid.
Then please... Just...
help me.
[breathes shakily]
I'll keep trying to find out
what happened to George.
but you have to stay quiet
and you have to keep your head down.
Stop wearing that watch!
It may be legal. but it draws attention.
When I find something. I'll send word.
A signal.
I promise.
What kind of signal?
You'll know it when you see it.
Anything I can do while I wait?
I have to figure out what this is.
and you need to trust me.
Yeah.
[Silo resident 12] You actually said
if he'd listened to his wife.
she'd still be alive?
And you wonder
why you never heard from him again.
Jules. y-you could've told me this before.
- He asked me to wait. so I waited.
- And you got no word. no sign.
Well. I'm sorry you didn't get the answers
you were hoping for.
but maybe you should take a day.
Maybe do something. Take your mind off it.
Maybe I should keep my mind on it.
I didn't show the sheriff everything.
Bottom half of the note George left me.
[Silo resident 12]
"I found what I was looking for."
Why didn't you show this to the sheriff?
George told me
that whatever he was looking for
was more dangerous than any relic.
He was afraid me even knowing
about it could get me sent out.
What was he looking for?
Jules. this is getting dangerous.
Yeah.
Um. I'll fix this later.
[stammers] No. you won't.
Yeah. No. I won't.
Um... Okay.
[Silo resident 12] Hey.
Try not to get yourself killed down there.
Yeah.
[door closes]
[Marnes]
I've got the judge's picks for sheriff.
Four mediocre candidates
just to shine a light
on the one she really wants.
- Paul Billings.
- I remember him. He was a deputy.
Yeah. in the Mids.
He was a good guy
till he abandoned us for Judicial.
He got married and he wanted better hours.
To be honest.
Paul Billings wouldn't be the worst.
I don't want someone who's not the worst.
[sighs] I keep thinking any minute
someone's gonna come through that door
and tell me there's an armed mob
coming up the stairs.
And 140 years of peace
is gonna go down the drain.
And my next thought is.
I have to go talk to Holston about this.
Yeah. I think the same thing
about ten times a day.
I wish he'd said who should take the job.
He did.
[Marnes breathes heavily]
- He left a note.
- Why did you wait until now to tell me?
Because it's ridiculous. and if anything.
it's a sign
he wasn't quite there at the end.
- Who'd he choose?
- You might wanna top off your drink.
[inhales deeply]
"In my final act as sheriff.
I. Holston Becker.
nominate Juliette Nichols of Mechanical
as my successor."
- Juliette Nichols?
- She's an engineer.
"Even if she refuses.
I ask that this badge.
my personal property. be given to her.
Holston Becker."
Why her?
Like I say.
he wasn't in his right mind at the end.
I wanna meet her.
- Are you sure?
- [sighs]
I said meet her. not give her the job.
I'll message
and have her start up tomorrow.
No. I'll go to her.
Oh. yeah? 144 levels?
[inhales deeply]
I just sent a sheriff out to clean.
I need to walk the Silo.
The people need to see their mayor.
[sighs]
[Juliette] You've got a lot of rope.
[George chuckling] Yeah.
What do you need it for?
[inhales deeply] To get where I'm going.
Okay. Where's that?
The past.
The past?
What are you looking for?
Well. what I'm looking for isn't nearly
as important as what I've found.
Mm-hmm?
You.
Wow. You idiot.
[chuckles]
Seriously. what are you looking for?
Uh. if I find it. I'll let you know.
- [laughing] Get off me... Okay. okay. okay.
- Tell me. Tell me. [laughs]
I think it's a door.
Hmm?
A door?
What do you mean. a door?
Uh. I... I saw it on a-a-an old drawing.
It's at the end of a short tunnel.
W-Well. what's behind it?
How do you even know it's real?
Well. I don't know.
That's why I need to find it.
It's somewhere down at the bottom.
At the bottom?
There's water. There's water down there.
Why would anyone put a door at the bottom?
- I know that the water scares you.
- Yeah. it scares me. George.
'Cause you sink in water
and you can't breathe.
What if you...
What if you fall off the rope?
What if you can't get back up again?
What if...
I'm gonna be careful.
[Juliette breathes shakily]
Okay. make me a deal. Um...
if you're gonna go down there.
I. uh...
I don't wanna know about it until after.
Okay?
Deal.
Okay.
[Juliette breathes deeply]
[breathes heavily. grunts]
[breathes heavily]
[breathing heavily]
[grunts. sighs]
[breathing shakily]
Okay.
[breathing heavily]
[grunting. panting]
[grunts]
[exhales sharply]
[screams]
[breathing heavily]
[gasping] No!
Fuck. [gasps]
[breathing heavily]
[groans. breathing heavily]